Avinash Baruli

Regional Manager - Cradle Life Sciences Pvt. Ltd.

Patna, Bihar avinashbaruli5_2ec@indeedemail.com +91 9031963199

An MCA by qualification and well experienced operational head having more than 6 years of experience in educational and skill development industry handling numerous woks like proposal making, public relation, fund raising, business development, real estate dealing for training centre, vendor management, liaisoning, , centre management, classroom management, staff management, assist in recruitment, attendance management etc. I have great pleasure in offering myself as a candidate in your reputed organization, to co-ordinate and organise various activities, events and programmes in keeping with your noble objective of rendering service to the people & the society.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Regional Manager

Cradle Life Sciences Pvt Ltd - Patna, Bihar May 2018 to Present

- Liaisoning with Govt. departments, ministries, NSDC, sector skill councils, assessment bodies, state level Govts like SRLM, panchayat, BDOs and SDOs
- Searching new projects using online tools, internals tie-ups and with the help of ministries. Preparing of proposals or tenders and its timely submission. Doing skill gap analysis
- Liaisoning with recruitment agencies or companies for placement supports, real estate management, vendor management, franchise development, signing of agreements, LoIs and MoUs
- Fund raising, instalment clearance, business development, invoice generation
- Infrastructure setup as per the SOPs, purchasing of equipment or tools, audit & assets management and AMC
- Recruitment or finding of potential candidate as per the requirement, documentation and background verification
- Branch and classroom management, marketing or mobilization strategy, attendance growth, organise events such as cultural activities, opening ceremonies, job fair and exhibitions
- Cash flow management paid to vendors, agencies and branches
- ERP handling, MIS generation and reporting such as daily work report, project detailing and budget, mobilization, enrolment and documentation, monthly attendance and placement tracking
- Training and development, SOP, counselling, screening, assessment or examination, bio-metric and CCTV backup and maintenance

Assistant Manager - Operations

ICA EDU SKILLS PRIVATE LIMITED - Kolkata, West Bengal August 2017 to May 2018

- New Infrastructure identification and finalization
- To maintain effective relationship with external clients for future
- Business generation

- Rotation of batches with no significant time gap
- Coordination with local administration, example Panchayat, SRLM, Employment Ex. to ensure appropriate

mobilization with desired ratio (SC, ST, Minority, OBC, GEN) Male/ Female

- To take part in screening of the candidates
- Infra compliances projects
- Welcome session for new approved candidates
- Handle student complaints/ problems and give solution & suggestion
- · Analysis of feedback of students taken during centre visit & inform the centre on same
- Maintain MIS on excel sheet & document verification
- Maintain the Govt. ERP portals
- Looks for the training quality

MIS Head

Cradle Life Sciences Pvt Ltd - Patna, Bihar June 2016 to August 2017

- Project Coordination and franchise development
- Infrastructure setup as per SOP
- Maintain MIS on excel sheet, document verification and maintain Govt. ERP portals
- Looks for the training quality (IT & MIS)
- Training contents, curriculum and assessment development
- Looking after the centre level issues
- · Coordination with centres and its staffs
- · Counselling, screening, parents meetings, rojgar mela, attendance and assessment management
- Coordinating for placement support
- Coordination with Govt. departments
- Proposal making and submission
- Hardware installation, maintenance and troubleshooting (Card Level Maintenance)
- Assist HR

IT Trainer

VISION INDIA SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED - Muzaffarpur, Bihar December 2014 to January 2016

- Conducts session for IT and soft skills, activation officer, data entry operator and MIS
- Development of ACLP, training contents, PPTs and assessment paper
- Hardware installation, maintenance and troubleshooting (card level)
- Maintained MIS or State Master for DDU-GKY
- · Assists centre manager in internal audits, documentations and maintenance of Standard Form (SF)
- Resolves Bio-Metric and CCTV issues and takes timely backup
- Assists in mobilization, counselling, screening and conducting aptitude test
- Assists in placement support and tracking

IT Trainer

ANUDIP FOUNDATION FOR SOCIAL WELFARE - Jamshedpur, Jharkhand June 2013 to December 2014

- Conducts session on IT and Soft skills for MAST project of America India Foundation (AIF)
- Training contents, curriculum and assessment development
- Hardware installation, maintenance and troubleshooting (Card Level)

- Maintains MIS on excel sheet, CMIS, documentation
- Coaching, counselling, screening
- Assists in franchisee development for MAST (Market Aligned Skills Training) program
- Assists in mobilization and placement
- Petty cash handling

Education

Master's in Computer Application in Computer Application

Mahatma Gandhi University

2014 to 2016

Bachelor in Information Technology in B.Sc. IT

ups and Kolhan University - Chaibasa, Jharkhand 2010 to 2013

Skills / IT Skills

• Public Relationship, Administration, MIS, Project Management, Business Development, Business Analysis, Training, Bidding, Tendering, Document Verify, MS Office, Liaison (7 years)

Online Profile

https://www.linkedin.com/in/avinash-baruli-a1927b97/

Additional Information

MAJOR AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Public Relationship Project Management Administration Recruitment Placement
- Business Development Business Analysis Training Decision Making Negotiation
- Problem Solving